Contact

Sacramento, CA tammythalern@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/tammy-thale-bsn-rn-phn-a98ba796 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Nursing Management Nursing Education Nursing Care

Certifications

Registered Nurse
Public Health Nurse
Bachelor of Science in Nursing

Tammy Thale BSN, RN, PHN

Bachelor of Science Nursing at Samuel Merritt University Sacramento, California Area

Summary

I began in the healthcare field in 1985, starting as a Nurses Aide at 19, LPN at 25 and RN at 34 in 2000. I was a trauma nurse in ICU and ER for 14 years. Hospice nurse coincided with the ER for three years from 2005-2008. I did ER travel nursing for the year 2008-2009. I left travel nursing in '09, for a permanent ER position at Kaiser Permanente (KP). In April 2014, I transferred within KP to Palliative Care. Educating inpatients and families on disease trajectory and helping them with goals of care. Working from my office one day a week following up outpatient with them and others referred by PCP's. It's a humbling, rewarding and often sacred space, being able to help and guide patients on their life decisions as their disease progresses, working on a Plan A and Plan B. I work with an outstanding team that is expanding greatly as the continuum in healthcare becomes a larger focus. This path in my career has taken me from bedside nursing to a consultant position. Daily, our team is working closely with physicians, social workers, chaplains, and discharge planners in often emotionally charged family meetings. I am honored to be in this position. Next career step for me with Kaiser will be obtaining my DNP with an FNP in Gerontology medicine to work with Palliative and Hospice pts.

Experience

Kaiser Permanente

11 years

Palliative Care RN

April 2014 - Present (6 years 4 months)

Our team assists patients and families dealing with advance life care planning decisions at the end of their chronic illnesses. It is our honor to be included in this very dynamic, vulnerable and labile time in their lives. We make sure their wishes are documented and followed as they have let us know before they become unable to speak for themselves.

ER RN

August 2009 - April 2014 (4 years 9 months)

Snowline Hospice Hospice Nurse September 2019 - Present (11 months)

Sacramento, California

Zuckerberg San Francisco General Hospital and Trauma Center Travel ER RN

August 2008 - August 2009 (1 year 1 month)

I contracted in two hospitals in Sacramento before this contract with SFG, when this contract ended is when I took my permanent position with Kaiser Permanente.

Halifax Health ER RN June 2007 - August 2008 (1 year 3 months)

Florida Hospital Memorial Medical Center & Florida Hospital Oceanside Hospice RN Case Manager June 2007 - January 2008 (8 months)

Good Shepard Hospice Hospice RN Triage Runner July 2005 - June 2007 (2 years)

48 hour every weekend position Sat 0800-Mon 0800

I had scheduled appointments during the mornings and remained on call for the entire 48 hours for patient needs, hospice "emergencies" and pronouncing death.

Tampa General Hospital
Travel ER RN
January 2006 - July 2006 (7 months)

Two consecutive contract's in a Level One Trauma Center ER

Lakeland Regional Medical Center ER RN March 2000 - July 2005 (5 years 5 months) Float LPN, hired into SICU during internship last semester of RN college. This is a surgical, open heart and trauma unit. Once an RN, I worked in the unit six months and transferred to the Level 2 ER Trauma center.

Winter Haven Hospital Neuro LPN June 1998 - June 1999 (1 year 1 month)

Watson Clinic LLP Clinic LPN July 1995 - July 1997 (2 years 1 month)

Doctor office duties as LPN, then I started college for consecutive RN and Liberal Arts degrees.

Lakeland Regional Medical Center Nephrology LPN June 1990 - June 1995 (5 years 1 month)

Started as a Nurses Aide on the Nephrology floor, in May 1991 after graduation of LPN school began doing primary nursing on this floor and was put through classes for certification in IV placement and Peritoneal Dialysis upon passing boards.

Education

Samuel Merritt University

Bachelor of Science Nursing, RN-BSN Nursing · (2016 - 2019)

Polk State College
Associate of Science (A.S.), Registered Nursing/Registered
Nurse · (1997 - 2000)

Polk State College
Associate of Arts (A.A.), Liberal Arts and Sciences/Liberal
Studies · (1997 - 2000)